Guide to the International Webern Society Records 1962-1989
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
International Webern Society Records
1962-1989
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 610
International Webern Society
4 containers. 2 linear feet of shelf space.
Correspondence, minutes, financial records, membership rosters, newsletters, and programs from musical performances, all related to this organization for the encouragement of study and performance of the music composed by Anton Webern. Correspondants include Peter Armstrong, Paul Hedwall, Wallace McKenzie, Hans Moldenhauer and Robert Riseling.
The International Webern Society was founded in 1962. The efforts of Hans Moldenhauer, a musicologist from Spokane, Washington, and biographer of Anton von Webern, were of considerable importance in bring the organization into being and long played a major role in the Society. The purpose of the organization was to encourage study and performance of the music of Anton von Webern. The organization was managed by officers at various locations, chiefly in the United States. The organization was dissolved in 1990.
Records of the International Webern Society consist of correspondence, minutes, fiscal records, membership lists, newsletters, and programs from music performances. Principal correspondents are Peter Armstrong, Paul Hedwall, Wallace McKenzie, Hans Moldenhauer, and Robert Riseling.
This collection is open for research use.
The records of the International Webern Society were acquired by the Washington State University Libraries in 1993 through William Brandt of Pullman, Secretary-Treasurer of the organization.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Webern, Anton 1883-1945--Societies, etc.; Moldenhauer, Hans; Armstrong, Peter; Hedwall, Paul, 1939-1979; McKenzie, Wallace; Riseling, Robert
International Webern Society --Archives; International Webern Society--Records and correspondence
Performing Arts
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Membership records, 3 card files, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
- Documents associated with organization of the Webern Society, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bank account records, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Membership lists and mailing label matrix sheets, 1967- 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bills, deposit records, checks and other fiscal records, 1967-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Banking records, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Banking records, 1971-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- deposit records, 1963-1967. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Cash account book, 1978-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Ledger of membership accounts, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Banking records, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Webern Memorial, Mittersall concert. Correspondence, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Officers' correspondence. Robb, Riseling, Hedwall, McKenzie, Moldenhauer, 1967-1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Officers' correspondence. Moldenhauer, McKenzie, Brandt, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence regarding the Webern Centennial Festival, Vienna, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence and information from members, 1967-1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Membership communications. Requests, dues, payments, 1967- 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence relative miscellaneous matters., 1967-1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- London Sinfonietta, South Bank. Webern Concert Series, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Programs. McKenzie's notes on Vienna performances, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Newsletters, 1967-1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Hans Moldenhauer. Letters, and related papers, 1968-1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Hans Moldenhauer. International Webern Society, Moldenhauer Archives, 1968-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
- Tape recording, with letter by Peter Armstrong, of recital in 1982--Webern, Scriabin, Schoenberg (Box 4, Folder 22)